<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Commission for Greenwich hospital</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1695</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 46 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 10 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A66120</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing W2312</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R19262</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12561154</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12561154</idno>
            <idno type="VID">63191</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A66120)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 63191)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 950:50)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Commission for Greenwich hospital</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>18 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Charles Bill, and the executrix of Thomas Newcomb ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1695.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Half-title.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Royal Hospital for Seamen at Greenwich.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:63191:1"/>
            <p>COMMISSION FOR Greenwich Hoſpital.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="royal_commission">
            <pb facs="tcp:63191:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:63191:2"/>
            <opener>
               <signed>
                  <hi>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>ILLIAM</hi> the Third, By the Grace of God, King of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, Scotland, France</hi> and <hi>Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> Defender of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </signed>
               <salute>To Our Dearly Beloved Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther-in-Law Prince <hi>George,</hi> He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditary of <hi>Denmark;</hi> The moſt Reverend Father in God, <hi>Thomas</hi> Arch-Biſhop of <hi>Canterbury,</hi> Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mate and Metropolitan of all <hi>England,</hi> and the Arch-Biſhop of <hi>Canterbury</hi> for the time being; Our Right Truſty and Wel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beloved Councellor Sir <hi>John Sommers</hi> Knight, Keeper of Our Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> and Our Chancellor of <hi>England,</hi> Keéper and Commiſſioners of Our Great Seal for the time being; Our Right Truſty and Right Entirely Beloved Couſin and Councellor <hi>Thomas</hi> Duke of <hi>Leeds,</hi> Preſident of Our Privy Council, and the Preſident of Our Privy Council for the time being; Our Right Truſty and Right Welbeloved Couſin and Councellor <hi>Thomas</hi> Earl of <hi>Pembrook</hi> and <hi>Montgomery,</hi> Keeper of Our Privy Seal, and the Keéper of Our Privy Seal for the time being; Our Right Truſty and Right Entirely Beloved Couſins and Councellors <hi>Henry</hi> Duke of <hi>Norfolk,</hi> Earl Marſhal of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land; William</hi> Duke of <hi>Devonſhire,</hi> Steward of Our Houſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold; <hi>Charles</hi> Duke of <hi>Bolton, Charles</hi> Duke of <hi>Shrewsbury,</hi> one of Our Principal Secretaries of State, and <hi>William</hi> Duke of <hi>Bedford;</hi> Our Right Truſty and Entirely Belo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:63191:3"/> Counſins and Councellors <hi>John</hi> Marquiſs of <hi>Normanby,</hi> and <hi>Charles Pawlett</hi> Eſquire, commonly called Marquiſs of <hi>Wincheſter;</hi> Our Right Truſty and Right Welbeloved Counſins and Councellors, <hi>Robert</hi> Earl of <hi>Lindſey,</hi> Great Chamberlain of <hi>England, Charles</hi> Earl of <hi>Dorſet</hi> and <hi>Middle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſex,</hi> Chamberlain of Our Houſhold; <hi>Aubrey</hi> Earl of <hi>Oxford, John</hi> Earl of <hi>Bridgewater, Thomas</hi> Earl of <hi>Stamford, John</hi> Earl of <hi>Bath, Daniel</hi> Earl of <hi>Nottingham, Lawrence</hi> Earl of <hi>Rocheſter, William</hi> Earl of <hi>Portland, Thomas</hi> Earl of <hi>Fauconberg, Charles</hi> Earl of <hi>Monmouth, Ralph</hi> Earl of <hi>Mountague, Richard</hi> Earl of <hi>Scarborough, Francis</hi> Earl of <hi>Bradford, Henry</hi> Earl of <hi>Romney,</hi> Maſter of Our Ordnance, and the Maſter of Our Ordnance for the time being; <hi>Richard</hi> Earl of <hi>Ranelagh</hi> in Our Kingdom of <hi>Ireland,</hi> Paymaſter of Our Forces; Our Right Truſty and Welbeloved Couſin and Councellor <hi>Charles</hi> Lord <hi>Durſley,</hi> commonly called <hi>Viſcount Durſley,</hi> Son and Heir Apparent of Our Right Truſty and Right Welbeloved Couſin <hi>George</hi> Earl of <hi>Berkley;</hi> The Right Reverend Father in God <hi>Henry</hi> Biſhop of <hi>London,</hi> and the Biſhop of that Seé for the time being; Our Right Truſty and Welbeloved Councellors <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert</hi> Lord <hi>Lexington, Charles</hi> Lord <hi>Cornwallis, Sidney</hi> Lord <hi>Godolphin,</hi> Firſt Commiſſioner of Our Treaſury; <hi>Henry</hi> Lord <hi>Capell, Thomas</hi> Lord <hi>Coningsby</hi> in Our Kingdom of <hi>Ireland, Charles Montague</hi> Eſquire, one of the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury, Chancellor and Vnder-Treaſurer of Our Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thequer, and the Chancellor and Vnder-Treaſurer of Our Exchequer for the time being; Sir <hi>John Trevor</hi> Knight, Speaker of Our Houſe of Commons, and Maſter of Our Rolls, and the Maſter of Our Rolls for the time being; Sir <hi>Robert Howard</hi> Knight, Auditor of the Receipt of Our Exchequer; <hi>Thomas Wharton</hi> Eſquire, Comptroller of Our Houſhold; Sir <hi>John Trenchard</hi> Knight, Our Principal Secretary of State, and Our Principal Secretary of State for the time being; Sir <hi>John Holt</hi> Kinght, Chief Juſtice Aſſigned to hold Pleas before Vs, and the Chief Iuſtice to be Aſſigned to hold Pleas before Vs for the time being; Sir <hi>John Louther</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>Henry Goodrick</hi> Knight and Baronet, Lieutenant General of Our Ordnance; <hi>Edward Ruſſell</hi> Eſquire, Firſt Commiſſioner of Our Admiralty, Treaſurer of Our Navy, and Admiral of Our Navy Royal; <hi>Richard Hampden</hi> and <hi>Hugh Buſcowen</hi> E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſquires; Our Truſty and Welbeloved Sir <hi>Stephen Fox</hi> Knight, one other of the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury; Sir <hi>William Trumball</hi> Knight, one other of the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury; <hi>John Smith</hi> Eſquire, one other of the Commiſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:63191:3"/> of Our Treaſury, and the Treaſurer of <hi>England;</hi> Treaſurer of Our Exchequer, and Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury for the time being; Sir <hi>John Louther</hi> of <hi>Whithaven</hi> Baronet; <hi>Henry Prieſtman</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Robert Auſtin</hi> Eſquire, Sir <hi>Robert Rich</hi> Knight and Baronet, Sir <hi>George Rook</hi> and Sir <hi>John Houblon</hi> Knights, which Six laſt named are alſo Commiſſioners of Our Admiralty, and the High Admiral of <hi>England,</hi> or the Commiſſioners for Executing the Office of High Admiral of <hi>England</hi> for the time being; Our Right Truſty and Right Welbeloved Couſins <hi>William</hi> Earl of <hi>Craven, Charles Bodvile</hi> Earl of <hi>Radnor, George</hi> Earl of <hi>Berkley,</hi> and <hi>Arthur</hi> Earl of <hi>Torrington,</hi> Our Truſty and Welbeloved Sir <hi>William Gregory</hi> Knight, Sir <hi>Gyles Eyre</hi> Knight, and Sir <hi>Samuel Eyre</hi> Knight, Iuſtices Aſſigned to hold Pleas before Vs, and the Iuſtices to be Aſſigned to hold Pleas be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore Vs for the time being; Sir <hi>George Treby</hi> Knight, Chief Iuſtice of Our Court of Common Pleas; Sir <hi>Edward Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vill</hi> Knight, Sir <hi>Thomas Rokeby</hi> Knight, and Sir <hi>John Powell</hi> Knight, Iuſtices of Our Court of Common Pleas, and the Chief Iuſtice and Iuſtices of the ſame Court for the time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing; Sir <hi>Nicholas Letchmore</hi> Knight, Sir <hi>John Turton</hi> Knight, Sir <hi>John Powell</hi> Knight, Batons, and <hi>George Bradbury</hi> Cur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſitor Baron of Our Court of Exchequer, and the Chief Baron, Barons of the Coife, and Curſitor Baron of Our Court of Exchequer for the time being; The moſt Reverend Father in God <hi>John</hi> Arch-Biſhop of <hi>York,</hi> Primate and Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tropolitan of <hi>England,</hi> and the Arch-Biſhop of <hi>York</hi> for the time being; The Right Reverend Father in God <hi>Nathaniel</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Dureſme, Peter</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Wincheſter, William</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Litchfield</hi> and <hi>Coventry, William</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Landaffe, Edward</hi> Biſhop of St. <hi>Aſaph, Thomas</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Rocheſter, Thomas</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſle, Jonathan</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Exon, Thomas</hi> Biſhop of <hi>St. Davids, Gil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Sarum, Humphrey</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Bangor, Edward</hi> Bi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhop of <hi>Worceſter, Symon</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Ely, Gilbert</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Hereford, Nicholas</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Cheſter, John</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Oxford, John</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Norwich, Richard</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Peterborough, Edward</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Glouceſter, Robert</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Chicheſter, Richard</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Bath</hi> and <hi>Wells, John</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Briſtol,</hi> and <hi>James</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Lincoln,</hi> and the ſeveral Biſhops of the ſame Seés for the time being; Our Truſty and Welbeloved Sir <hi>Edward Ward</hi> Knight, Our Attorny General; Sir <hi>Thomas Trevor</hi> Knight, Our Solicitor General; <hi>Samuel Travers</hi> Eſquire, Surveyor General of Our Lands; Sir <hi>Chriſtopher Wrenn</hi> Knight, Surveyor General of Our Works; Our Truſty and Welbeloved Sir <hi>Thomas Lane</hi> Knight, Mayor of Our City of <hi>London,</hi> and the Mayor of the ſame City for the time being; Sir <hi>Robert Clayton,</hi> Sir
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:63191:4"/> 
                  <hi>Patience Ward,</hi> Sir <hi>John Moor,</hi> Sir <hi>William Pritchard,</hi> Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Jeffery,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Stamp,</hi> Sir <hi>John Fleet,</hi> Sir <hi>William Aſhhurſt,</hi> Sir <hi>Jonathan Raymond,</hi> Sir <hi>Peter Daniel,</hi> Sir <hi>Samuel Daſhwood,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Kinſey,</hi> Sir <hi>John Parſons,</hi> Sir <hi>Edward Clark,</hi> Sir <hi>Humphrey Edwin,</hi> Sir <hi>Francis Child,</hi> Sir <hi>Richard Levett,</hi> Sir <hi>William Gore,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Cooke,</hi> Sir <hi>James Houblon,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Abney,</hi> Sir <hi>William Hedges,</hi> Knights, <hi>Thomas Darwin</hi> and <hi>Joſeph Smart</hi> Eſquires, Aldermen of Our City of <hi>London,</hi> and all and every the Aldermen of the ſame City for the time being; Our Truſty and Welbeloved <hi>Edmond Bowyer</hi> of <hi>Camberwell</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Michael Godfrey</hi> E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſquire, Sir <hi>Leonard Robinſon</hi> Knight, Chamberlain of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don;</hi> Sir <hi>John Morden,</hi> Sir <hi>John Banks,</hi> Sir <hi>Joſiah Child,</hi> Sir <hi>Peter Vandeput,</hi> Sir <hi>William Ruſſell,</hi> Sir <hi>Jeremy Sambrook,</hi> Sir <hi>Gabriel Roberts,</hi> Sir <hi>John Foche,</hi> Sir <hi>Henry Furnes,</hi> Sir <hi>William Scawen,</hi> Sir <hi>Joſeph Herne</hi> Knights, Sir <hi>Richard Onſlow</hi> Baro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>net, <hi>John Lock,</hi> Gilbert <hi>Heathcott,</hi> and <hi>Arthur Shallott</hi> Eſquires, Our Truſty and Welbeloved Sir <hi>Richard Haddock,</hi> Sir <hi>Cloud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſley Shovell</hi> Knights, <hi>Edmund Dummer, Charles Sergiſon, Samuel Pett, Thomas Wilſhaw, Dennis Liddall, Benjamin Tinewell</hi> E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſquires, Principal Officers of Our Navy, and the Principal Officers in the nature of Commiſſioners of Our Navy for the time being, and Our Truſty and Welbeloved Sir <hi>Charles Hedges</hi> Knight, Iudge of Our Supreme Court of Admiral<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, <hi>Henry Guy</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Thomas Papillon</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Thomas Weſtern</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Charles Duncomb</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Peter Houblon</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Edmund Bolter</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Thomas Firmin,</hi> and <hi>William Lowndes</hi> Gent. Our Truſty and Welbeloved <hi>John Hill,</hi> EſQ; Maſter and Aſſiſtant of Trinity Houſe of <hi>Deptford Strond,</hi> Captain <hi>Samuel Rutter,</hi> Captain <hi>John Bowers,</hi> Captain <hi>John Conaway,</hi> Captain <hi>Roger Paxton,</hi> Captain <hi>John Benbow,</hi> Sir <hi>Matthew Andrews,</hi> Captain <hi>John Nicholls,</hi> Captain <hi>Ralph San<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſon, Robert</hi> Lord <hi>Lucas,</hi> Sir <hi>Henry Sheer</hi> Knight, <hi>James Southern</hi> Eſquire, Captain <hi>Robert Fiſher,</hi> Captain <hi>George Phen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny,</hi> Captain <hi>Samuel Atkinſon,</hi> Captain <hi>Henry Greenhill,</hi> Captain <hi>Henry Risby,</hi> Captain <hi>Balthazar St. Mitchell,</hi> Captain <hi>Humphrey Ayles,</hi> Captain <hi>John Jacob,</hi> Captain <hi>William Cruft,</hi> Captain <hi>William Gutteridge,</hi> Captain <hi>John Hazelwood,</hi> and the Maſter and all and every the Wardens, Aſſiſtants and Elder Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren of Trinity Houſe of <hi>Deptford Strond</hi> for the time being, Greéting.</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>Whereas We are extreamly deſirous that the Trade, Navigation and Naval Strength of this Our Realm of <hi>England</hi> (whereupon the Safety and Flouriſhing State thereof does ſo much depend) ſhould by all Proper Means be Promoted and Advanced. And whereas We are per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwaded
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:63191:4"/> that nothing will more effectually Contribute there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to, then the Endeavouring, by due and fitting Encourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, to encreaſe the Number of <hi>Engliſh</hi> Seamen, as well for the Strengthning of Our Navy Royal, and better Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forming the Naval Services of Vs, Our Heirs and Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors, as for the Supplying and Carrying on the Occaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons and Buſineſs of Our Merchants, and other Our Lo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving Subjects, Intereſted in Trade, Commerce, Fiſhing, Plantation, Diſcovery, and other Affairs relating to Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vigation. And whereas the Sea-fairing Men of this Kingdom, have for a long time Diſtinguiſhed themſelves throughout the World by their Induſtry and Skilfulneſs in their proper Employments, and by their Courage and Conſtancy, manifeſted in Engagements and Hazards, for the Defence and Honour of their Native Countrey; and no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing is more likely to continue this their Ancient Reputa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and to invite greater Numbers of Our Subjects to betake themſelves to the Sea, than the making ſome Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petent Proviſion, That Seamen, who by Age, Wounds or other Accidents, ſhall become Diſabled for further Service at Sea, and ſhall not be in a Condition to maintain them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves Comfortably, may not fall under Hardſhips and Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeries, but may be Supported at the Publick Charge: And that the Children of ſuch Diſabled Seamen, and alſo the Widows and Children of ſuch Seamen as ſhall happen to be Slain in Sea-Service, may in ſome Reaſonable Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner be Provided for and Educated. And whereas having frequently Reflected upon the Premiſſes ſince Our Acceſſion to the Crown, We have Determined with Our Selves, to Erect and Eſtabliſh a Hoſpital for the Purpoſes aforeſaid. And although by reaſon of the Expenſive War in which We have been, and are at preſent Engaged, We have not been able to Carry on the ſaid Good and Pious Purpoſes, to ſuch Effect as We have deſired: Yet in order to begin to put the ſame in Execution, We and Our late moſt Dear Conſort the Queén, did by Our Letters Patents under Our Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing Date the Twenty fifth of <hi>October</hi> laſt paſt, Give and Grant unto you the ſaid Sir <hi>John Sommers, Thomas</hi> Duke of <hi>Leeds, Thomas</hi> Earl of <hi>Pembrook</hi> and <hi>Montgomery, Charles</hi> Duke of <hi>Shrewsbury, Sidney</hi> Lord <hi>Godolphin,</hi> Sir <hi>John Trenchard, Edward Ruſſell,</hi> Sir <hi>Stephen Fox,</hi> Sir <hi>John Louther</hi> of <hi>Whithaven,</hi> Sir <hi>William Aſhhurſt,</hi> Sir <hi>Robert Clayton,</hi> Sir <hi>Patience Ward,</hi> Sir <hi>John Moor,</hi> and Sir <hi>William Pritchard,</hi> and to your Heirs and Aſſigns for ever, all that Piece or Parcel of Ground, Scituate, Lying and Being within the Pariſh of <hi>Eaſt-Greenwich,</hi> in Our
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:63191:5"/> County of <hi>Kent,</hi> and being Parcel, or reputed Parcel of Our Manor of <hi>Eaſt-Greenwich</hi> aforeſaid, containing in the whole by Admeaſurement, Eight Acres, Two Roods, and Thirty two Square Perches, be the ſame more or leſs, as the ſaid Ground is now Marked, Staked or otherwiſe Set out, in which Admeaſurement, the Ground is Signed for a Way or Paſſage to lead through the Premiſſes, and therein mentioned to be excepted, is comprehended and reckoned, which ſaid Piece or Parcel of Ground is Butted and Bounded, as in the ſaid Letters Patents is expreſſed; And all that Capital Meſſuage lately built or in building by Our Royal Vncle King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, and ſtill re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maining unfiniſhed, commonly called by the Name of Our Pallace at <hi>Greenwich,</hi> ſtanding upon the Piece or Parcel of Ground aforeſaid, and ſeveral other Edifices and Buildings, and other things in the ſaid Letters Patents mentioned, except as therein is excepted; To the intent nevertheleſs that the aforeſaid Premiſſes, and every part thereof, ſhall be Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verted and Employed unto and for the Vſe and Service of Our Hoſpital for the Relief of Seamen, their Widows and Children, and Encouragement of Navigation in ſuch man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner as is therein expreſſed, and as by the Letters Patents aforeſaid, (relation being thereunto had) may more fully appear. And as We are fully Satisfied, that the Execting of ſuch an Hoſpital, as aforeſaid, will be of Great Bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit and Advantage to this Our Kingdom; ſo alſo taking into Our Royal Conſideration, that the Conſtituting and Eſtabliſhing a Foundation of that Nature, and the Fra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming of Rules and Statutes for the Government thereof, in ſuch a Manner as may beſt Anſwer what is thereby In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended and Deſigned, is a Matter of Great Difficulty, and ſuch as does require Mature Deliveration and Advice; know ye therefore that We Repoſing eſpecial Truſt and Confidence in your known Diſcretions, Abilities and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tegrities, Have Nominated, Authorized and Conſtituted, and do by theſe Preſents, Nominate, Authorize and Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point you the ſaid Prince <hi>George</hi> Hereditary of <hi>Denmark, Thomas</hi> Arch-Biſhop of <hi>Canterbury,</hi> and the Arch-Biſhop of <hi>Canterbury</hi> for the time being; Sir <hi>John Sommers,</hi> and Our Chancellor of <hi>England,</hi> Keeper and Commiſſioners of Our Great Seal for the time being; <hi>Thomas</hi> Duke of <hi>Leeds,</hi> and the Preſident of Our Privy Council for the time being; <hi>Thomas</hi> Earl of <hi>Pembrook</hi> and <hi>Montgomery,</hi> and the Keeper of Our Privy Seal for the time being; <hi>Henry</hi> Duke of <hi>Norfolk, William</hi> Duke of <hi>Devonſhire, Charles</hi> Duke of <hi>Bolton, Charles</hi> Duke of <hi>Shrewsbury,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Duke of <hi>Bedford, John</hi> Marquiſs of
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:63191:5"/> 
               <hi>Normanby,</hi> and <hi>Charles Pawlett</hi> Eſquire, commonly called Marquiſs of <hi>Wincheſter; Robert</hi> Earl of <hi>Lindſey, Charles</hi> Earl of <hi>Dorſet</hi> and <hi>Middleſex, Aubrey</hi> Earl of <hi>Oxford, John</hi> Earl of <hi>Bridgewater, Thomas</hi> Earl of <hi>Stamford, John</hi> Earl of <hi>Bath, Daniel</hi> Earl of <hi>Nottingham, Lawrence</hi> Earl of <hi>Roche<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter, William</hi> Earl of <hi>Portland, Thomas</hi> Earl of <hi>Fauconberg, Charles</hi> Earl of <hi>Monmouth, Ralph</hi> Earl of <hi>Montague, Richard</hi> Earl of <hi>Scarborough, Francis</hi> Earl of <hi>Bradford, Henry</hi> Earl of <hi>Romney,</hi> and the Maſter of Our Ordnance for the time being; <hi>Richard</hi> Earl of <hi>Ranelagh, Charles</hi> Lord <hi>Durſley,</hi> com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monly called <hi>Viſcount Durſley, Henry</hi> Biſhop of <hi>London,</hi> and the Biſhop of that Seé for the time being; <hi>Robert</hi> Lord <hi>Lexington, Charles</hi> Lord <hi>Cornwallis, Sidney</hi> Lord <hi>Godolphin, Henry</hi> Lord <hi>Capell, Thomas</hi> Lord <hi>Coningsby, Charles Montague,</hi> and the Chancellor and Vnder-Treaſurer of Our Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer for the time being; Sir <hi>John Trevor,</hi> and the Maſter of Our Rolls for the time being; Sir <hi>Robert Howard, Thomas Wharton,</hi> Sir <hi>John Trenchard,</hi> and Our Principal Secretaries of State for the time being; Sir <hi>John Holt,</hi> and the Chief Iuſtice to be Aſſigned to hold Pleas before Vs for the time being; Sir <hi>John Louther</hi> of <hi>Louther,</hi> Sir <hi>Henry Goodrick, Edward Ruſſell, Richard Hampden, Hugh Buſcowen,</hi> Sir <hi>Stephen Fox,</hi> Sir <hi>William Trumball, John Smith,</hi> and the Treaſurer of <hi>England,</hi> Treaſurer of Our Exchequer, and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners of Our Treaſury for the time being; Sir <hi>John Louther</hi> of <hi>Whithaven, Henry Prieſtman, Robert Auſtin,</hi> Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Rich,</hi> Sir <hi>George Rook,</hi> Sir <hi>John Houblon,</hi> and the High Admiral of <hi>England,</hi> or the Commiſſioners for Executing the Office of High Admiral of <hi>England</hi> for the time being; <hi>William</hi> Earl of <hi>Craven, Charles Bodvile</hi> Earl of <hi>Radnor, George</hi> Earl of <hi>Berkley,</hi> and <hi>Arthur</hi> Earl of <hi>Torrington,</hi> Sir <hi>William Gregory,</hi> Sir <hi>Gyles Eyre</hi> and <hi>Samuel Eyre,</hi> and the Iuſtices to be Aſſigned to hold Pleas before Vs for the time being; Sir <hi>George Treby,</hi> Sir <hi>Edward Nevill,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Rokeby</hi> and Sir <hi>John Powell,</hi> and the Chief Iuſtice and Iuſtices of the Court of Common Pleas for the time being; Sir <hi>Nicholas Lechmere,</hi> Sir <hi>John Turton,</hi> Sir <hi>John Powell,</hi> and <hi>George Bradbury,</hi> and the Chief Baron, Barons of the Coife, and Curſitor Baron of Our Court of Exchequer for the time being; <hi>John</hi> Arch-Biſhop of <hi>York,</hi> and the Arch-Biſhop of <hi>York</hi> for the time being; <hi>Nathaniel</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Dureſme, Peter</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Wincheſter, William</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Litchfield</hi> and <hi>Coventry, William</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Landaffe, Edward</hi> Biſhop of St. <hi>Aſaph, Thomas</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Rocheſter, Thomas</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſle, Jonathan</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Exon, Thomas</hi> Biſhop of <hi>St. Davids, Gil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Sarum, Humphrey</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Bangor, Edward</hi> Bi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhop of <hi>Worceſter, Symon</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Ely, Gilbert</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Hereford,</hi>
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:63191:6"/> 
               <hi>Nicholas</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Cheſter, John</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Oxford, John</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Norwich, Richard</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Peterborough, Edward</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Glouceſter, Robert</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Chicheſter, Richard</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Bath</hi> and <hi>Wells, John</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Briſtol,</hi> and <hi>James</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Lincoln,</hi> and the ſeveral Biſhops of the ſame Seés for the time being; Sir <hi>Edward Ward,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Trevor, Samuel Travers,</hi> Sir <hi>Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtopher Wrenn,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Lane,</hi> and the Mayor of Our City of <hi>London</hi> for the time being; Sir <hi>Robert Clayton,</hi> Sir <hi>Patience Ward,</hi> Sir <hi>John Moor,</hi> Sir <hi>William Pritchard,</hi> Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Jeffery,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Stamp,</hi> Sir <hi>John Fleet,</hi> Sir <hi>William Aſhhurſt,</hi> Sir <hi>Jonathan Raymond,</hi> Sir <hi>Peter Daniel,</hi> Sir <hi>Samuel Daſhwood,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Kinſey,</hi> Sir <hi>John Parſons,</hi> Sir <hi>Edward Clark,</hi> Sir <hi>Humphrey Edwin,</hi> Sir <hi>Francis Child,</hi> Sir <hi>Richard Levett,</hi> Sir <hi>William Gore,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Cooke,</hi> Sir <hi>James Houblon,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Abney,</hi> Sir <hi>William Hedges, Thomas Darwin</hi> and <hi>Joſeph Smart,</hi> and all and every the Aldermen of the ſame City for the time being; <hi>Edmund Bowyer, Michael Godfrey,</hi> Sir <hi>Leonard Robinſon,</hi> Sir <hi>John Morden,</hi> Sir <hi>John Banks,</hi> Sir <hi>Joſiah Child,</hi> Sir <hi>Peter Vandeput,</hi> Sir <hi>William Ruſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſell,</hi> Sir <hi>Jeremy Sambrook,</hi> Sir <hi>Gabriel Roberts,</hi> Sir <hi>John Foche,</hi> Sir <hi>Henry Furnes,</hi> Sir <hi>William Scawen,</hi> Sir <hi>Joſeph Horne,</hi> Sir <hi>Richard Onſlow</hi> Baronet, <hi>John Lock, Gilbert Heathcott,</hi> and <hi>Arthur Shallott</hi> Eſquires; Sir <hi>Richard Haddock,</hi> Sir <hi>Cloudſley Shovell, Edmund Dummer, Charles Sergiſon, Samuel Pett, Thomas Wilſhaw, Dennis Liddall, Benjamin Tinewell,</hi> and the Principall Officers in the nature of Commiſſioners of Our Navy for the time being; Sir <hi>Charles Hedges, Henry Guy, Thomas Papillon, Thomas Weſtern, Charles Duncomb, Peter Houblon, Edmund Bolter, Thomas Firmin,</hi> and <hi>William Lowndes, John Hill,</hi> Captain <hi>Samuel Rutter,</hi> Captain <hi>John Bowyers,</hi> Captain <hi>John Conaway,</hi> Captain <hi>Roger Paxton,</hi> Captain <hi>John Benbow,</hi> Sir <hi>Matthew Andrews,</hi> Captain <hi>John Nicholls,</hi> Captain <hi>Ralph Sanderſon, Robert</hi> Lord <hi>Lucas,</hi> Sir <hi>Henry Shere, James Sou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thern,</hi> Captain <hi>Robert Fiſher,</hi> Captain <hi>George Phenney,</hi> Captain <hi>Samuel Atkinſon,</hi> Captain <hi>Henry Greenhill,</hi> Captain <hi>Henry Risby,</hi> Captain <hi>Balthazar St. Mitchell,</hi> Captain <hi>Humphrey Ayles,</hi> Captain <hi>John Jacob,</hi> Captain <hi>William Cruft,</hi> Captain <hi>William Gutteridge,</hi> Captain <hi>John Hazelwood,</hi> and the Maſter and all and every the Wardens, Aſſiſtants and Elder Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren of Trinity Houſe of <hi>Deptford Strond</hi> for the time being, to be Our Commiſſioners for the Purpoſes herein after mentioned. And to the end that Our Royal Purpoſe and Intention herein may the better take Effect, Our Will and Pleaſure is, and We do hereby Order, Direct and Appoint, That you do, from time to time, Meét together at ſome Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient Place for the Execution of this Our Commiſſion,
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:63191:6"/> and that at your firſt or ſome other Subſequent Meéting or Meétings, ſo many of you as ſhall be then preſent, of whom any one or more of you being of Our Privy Council, and any one or more of you the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury, and any one or more of you the Commiſſioners for Executing the Office of Our High Admiral of <hi>England</hi> for the time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, to be Threé at the leaſt, do conſider of ſuch Proper and Fit Methods as you ſhall judge moſt Expedient to be Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerved in Executing the ſame. And We do alſo by theſe Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſents Authorize and Impower you Our ſaid Commiſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners, or any Seven or more of you, of whom any one or more of you Our Privy Councellors, and any one or more of you the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury, and any one or more of you the Commiſſioners for Executing the Office of Our High Admiral of <hi>England</hi> for the time being, to be Threé at the leaſt, to call to your Aid and Aſſiſtance, ſuch Perſons as you ſhall think fit to Aſſiſt and Adviſe you in the Due and Effectual Execution of this Our Commiſſion, and out of your own Number, as often as you ſhall judge it Expe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dient, to Appoint and Conſtitute ſuch and ſo many Sub-Committeés for the better Managing and Carrying on Our ſaid Purpoſe and Intention in this Our Commiſſion, and to Inveſt them with ſuch Powers as you ſhall think fit to intruſt them with, purſuant to the Powers hereby given to your ſelves, and to Revoke or make Void the ſame, and Revive and make a New the ſaid Sub-Committeés ſo often as you ſhall think neédful, as aforeſaid. And We do by theſe preſents Authorize and Require you our ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, or any Seven or more of you, of whom any one or more of you Our Privy Councellors, and any one or more of you the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury, and any one or more of you the Commiſſioners for Executing the Office of Our High Admiral of <hi>England</hi> for the time being, to be Threé at the leaſt, calling to your Aſſiſtance Our Surveyor General of Our Works, and alſo ſuch other Artiſts and Perſons as you ſhall think fit, to conſider what part, and how much of the Structures and Buildings now ſtanding upon the Pieces or Parcels of Ground con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained in Our Grant above mentioned, will be unfit or not ſerviceable for the Hoſpital hereby intended to be Exected, and in what manner ſuch of the preſent Structures as you ſhall think fit to ſtand may beſt be Altered, Fitted and Prepared for the Vſe and Service of the ſaid Hoſpital, in Order to Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſent the ſame to Vs with all convenient ſpeéd. And We do alſo Authorize and Require you Our ſaid Commiſſioners, or any Seven or more of you, of whom Three or more, to
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:63191:7"/> be ſuch as aforeſaid, forthwith, according to the beſt of your Iudgments and Diſcretions, to prepare One or more Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>del or Models of ſuch Buildings, Works, Erections and Conveniencies, as you ſhall think moſt fit and proper to be Erected and Made, in and upon the Premiſſes by Vs Grant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, as aforeſaid, for the Vſe of the ſaid intended Hoſpital, with ſuch Schemes or Draughts as may beſt Explain the ſame, and with all convenient Speed to preſent ſuch Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>del or Models to Vs for Our Royal Approvation. And We do further hereby Authorize and Impower you Our ſaid Commiſſioners, or any Seven or more of you, of whom Three or more, to be ſuch, as aforeſaid, Calling to your Aſſiſtance Our Attorney or Sollicitor General, or any other of Our Council Learned in the Law for the time being, or ſuch others as you ſhall think meet, to Conſider of, and Prepare a Charter or Charters of Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dation of ſuch Hoſpital, and alſo ſuch Statutes, Conſtitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, Orders and Ordinances as may be Proper for the Foundation, Perpetual Management, Order, Rule and good Government of the ſame, and of the Poor People, Officers, Servants and others that ſhall be entertained in and about the ſame, and for and concerning all other Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters and things relating thereto, and to preſent the ſame to Vs for Our Royal Conſideration. And whereas the Great and Earneſt Deſire which We have to ſet about ſo Good and Pious a Work hath Engaged Vs to begin the ſame at this time, although by Reaſon of the preſent Neceſſity of Our Affairs, We cannot Advance ſo conſiderable Sums, for the beginning and Carrying on the ſaid Works, as We do De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire and Intend, and by Gods Bleſſing in times of Peace ſhall be enabled to do: Yet nevertheleſs, as a further In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance of Our Princely Zeal for Advancing the ſaid De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign, We have Reſolved and Determined, and do hereby Declare and make Known, That from henceforth We will yearly cauſe to be Iſſued and Paid out of Our Treaſure, at and upon the Feaſt of the Birth of our Lord <hi>Chriſt,</hi> in every Year, or at ſuch other time in every Year as ſhall be deſired by Our ſaid Commiſſioners, or any Seven or more of them, the Sum of Two thouſand Pounds, for and to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the Edifying, Perfecting and Endowing the ſaid Hoſpital. And to that end, We do hereby, for Vs, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Require the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury, and Vnder-Treaſurer of Our Exchequer now being, and the Treaſurer of Our Exchequer, and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners of the Treaſury, and Vnder-Treaſurer of the Exchequer, of Vs, Our Heirs or Succeſſors for the time
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:63191:7"/> being, without any further or other Warrant to be had or obtained from Vs, Our Heirs or Succeſſors in that behalf, from time to time, to direct their Warrants or Orders for the Payment of the ſaid yearly Sum of Two thouſand Pounds, as aforeſaid, out of ſuch of Our Treaſure of Vs, Our Heirs or Succeſſors, as ſhall not be Appropriated to other Vſes, to the ſaid Treaſurer for the ſaid Hoſpital hereby Appointed, or to ſuch other Treaſurer or Treaſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers as ſhall be Appointed, as herein after is Directed, at the ſaid Feaſt of the Birth of Our Lord <hi>Chriſt</hi> in every Year, or at ſuch other times in every Year as ſhall be deſired by Our ſaid Commiſſioners, or any Seven or more of them, as aforeſaid, during the Continuance of this Our Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion. And having no Doubt but that Great Numbers of Our good Subjects will be diſpoſed to follow Our Example, and will, with great Chearfulneſs and Readineſs, Contribute to the Advancing ſo Charitable a Deſign, which, beſides the Relief of ſo many Poor Diſabled and Neceſſitous Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, will prove of Great Advantage to the Kingdom, in the increaſing the Navigation and Naval Strength thereof, by Encouraging Fit Perſons to betake themſelves to Sea-Service as ſoon as Our Royal Intentions in the Premiſſes ſhall be made known, and that their Aſſiſting Vs in the Building and Endowing the ſaid Hoſpital will be moſt High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Acceptable to Vs; We do by theſe Preſents Authorize and Impower you Our ſaid Commiſſioners, or any Seven or more of you, and We do by theſe Preſents Give and Grant to you, or any Seven or more of you, full Power and Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority to Take and Receive from ſuch of Our good Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects, as ſhall be Piouſly Diſpoſed to Contribute towards the Erecting and Endowing of the ſaid Hoſpital, all ſuch Vo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luntary Gifts or Subſcriptions of or for any Sum or Sums of Money, Goods or Chattels, or of or for any Eſtate or Intereſt in any Manors, Lands, Tenements, Rents, He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditaments, or other Matters or Things whatſoever, which any Perſon or Perſons ſhall be willing to Give, Limit, Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point or Beſtow for or towards the Building, Furniſhing or Endowing of the Hoſpital aforeſaid, and for cauſing to be Collected and Received whatſoever ſhall be Given, Contri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buted, Bequeathed, Deſigned or Appointed for that Vſe, by the Hands of the Treaſurer that ſhall be hereafter Appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to Receive the ſame. And to the end that Our Intenti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons in the Premiſſes may be better known to Our Loving Subjects, We do Require you to cauſe Publick Notification of theſe Preſents, or the Tenor or Scope thereof, to be made in ſuch Places, or by ſuch Ways and Means, as you ſhall
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:63191:8"/> think moſt Conducible to the Furtherance of the ſaid Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity. And We do alſo by theſe Preſents Authorize and Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>power you Our ſaid Commiſſioners, or any Seven or more of you, of whom any one or more of you Our Privy Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellors, and any one or more of you the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury, and any one or more of you the Commiſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners for Executing the Office of Our High Admiral of <hi>England</hi> for the time being, to be Threé at the leaſt, in caſe you ſhall find the ſame to be neceſſary for Carrying on the Deſign and Intention of this Our Commiſſion, by In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruments or Writings under your Hands and Seals, to Depute and Subſtitute ſuch Perſons as you ſhall think fit to Intruſt to take ſuch Subſcriptions, as aforeſaid, and to Collect or Bring in the Moneys which ſhall be Contribu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, Bequeathed, Deſigned or Appointed for the Vſes afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, to the Hands of the Treaſurer or Receiver General hereafter Appointed, and to Diſplace or Diſcharge ſuch Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtitutes or Deputies, or any of them, and to Appoint others in the Place of them or any of them, from time to time, as you ſhall ſeé cauſe, and to Settle, Eſtabliſh and Appoint ſuch Cheques, Comptrols and Orders, as you ſhall think neceſſary or ſafe, for the full and due Charging of the Treaſurer and Receiver General, and alſo the ſaid Deputies, Subſtitutes and all and every other Perſon and Perſons whatſoever, who ſhall Receive, or be Chargeable with any Moneys or other Profits for the ſaid Charitable Vſe or Purpoſe, to Anſwer, Pay or Account for the ſame. And that you Our ſaid Commiſſioners, or any Seven or more of you, from time to time, as often as you, or any Seven of you, ſhall Suſpect or Doubt of any Concealment, Fraud, or any Deceitful or Indirect Practice in reference to any Moneys, or other things Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed, Contributed, Given, Bequeathed, or Appointed to the ſaid Vſe, ſhall and may enquire thereof by the Exami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation of Witneſſes upon Oath (which you have hereby Power to Adminiſter) or by any other Lawful Ways and Means, whereby the truth of the Matter in all ſuch Caſes may beſt be Known, and to proceed thereupon with Effect. And Our Pleaſure is, and We do hereby Require and Command, That you Our ſaid Commiſſioners, or any Seven or more of you do, from time to time, Certifie to the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury now being, or to the Treaſurer or Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury for the time being, the Names of the Perſons, Societies, Bodies Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>litick or Corporate, who ſhall Subſcribe or Contribute, Give, Deviſe or Appoint any Moneys, or any Real Eſtate, or other Matters or Things towards this Charitable De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign,
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:63191:8"/> with the Sums of Money, Goods, Chattels, Eſtates, or other things by them reſpectively Contributed, Given, Limited, Appointed or Deviſed, to the end a Perpetual Memorial may be made of ſuch Well-diſpoſed Perſons, who ſhall become Benefactors, as aforeſaid, and whereby the Treaſurer or Receiver General may be Charged with more certainty in his Accounts. And in regard We do Confide very much in the Ability and Faithfulneſs of Our Truſty and Welbeloved <hi>John Evelyn <hi>ſenior</hi>
               </hi> Eſquire; We have No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minated, Aſſigned and Appointed, and We do hereby No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minate, Aſſign and Appoint him the ſaid <hi>John Evelyn <hi>ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nior,</hi>
               </hi> to be the Treaſurer and Receiver General of all the Moneys, and other Profits which ſhall be Subſcribed, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tributed, Given, Bequeathed, Deviſed, Deſigned or Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, to or for the Building, Furniſhing or Endowing of the ſaid Hoſpital, or for any Matter or Thing Relating thereunto, to continue in that Truſt during Our Plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure. And in Caſe of his Death or Removal, We do here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by give full Power and Authority to you Our ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, or any Seven or more of you, whereof any one or more of you Our Privy Councellors, and any one or more of you the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury, and any one or more of you the Commiſſioners for Executing the Office of High Admiral of <hi>England</hi> for the time being, to be Threé at the leaſt, from time to time, to Appoint one or more fit Perſon or Perſons to the ſaid Place or Truſt of Treaſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rer and Receiver General; and ſuch Perſon or Perſons, from time to time, to Remove or Diſplace as you ſhall ſee Cauſe. And Our Pleaſure is, That the Treaſurer or Receiver General for the time being, ſhall have full Power and Authority, and he is hereby fully Authorized, from time to time, upon the Receipt or Receipts of any Sum or Sums of Money, or other Profits for the Purpoſes aforeſaid, or any of them, to give an Acquittance or Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quittances for the ſame, which ſhall be good and ſufficient Diſcharges to all Intents and Purpoſes whatſoever. And the ſaid Treaſurer or Receiver General for the time being, in his Receipts, Payments and Accounts, ſhall be ſubject to ſuch Inſpection, Examination and Comptrol, as you or any Seven or more of you, whereof ſuch as are before Appointed for a Special <hi>Quorum</hi> to be Three at the leaſt, ſhall Eſtabliſh or Appoint. And We do hereby, for Vs, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Strictly Command, Enjoyn and Require, That none of the Moneys or other things which ſhall be Given, Contributed, Deviſed, Bequeathed, Deſigned or Appointed, as aforeſaid, ſhall be Diverted,
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:63191:9"/> Iſſued or Applied, or be in any wiſe Applicable to any Vſe or Purpoſe whatſoever, other then to the Charitable Purpoſes before mentioned, or ſome of them, or to Defray neceſſary Charges relating thereunto. And to the end that the Building and Fitting of the ſaid Hoſpital may be Carried on with as much ſpeed as is poſſible, We do by theſe Preſents give full Power and Authority to you Our ſaid Commiſſioners, or any Seven or more of you, of which any one or more of you Our Privy Councellors, or any one or more of you the Commiſſioners of Our Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſury, and any one or more of you the Commiſſioners for Executing the Office of Our High Admiral of <hi>England</hi> for the time being, to be Three at the leaſt, when, and as ſoon after as We ſhall have Approved under Our Sign Manual, your Report or Certificate in that behalf, to take down and demoliſh, or cauſe to be taken down and demoliſhed ſo much of the Buildings and Structures now ſtanding upon the Ground by Vs Granted, as aforeſaid, as ſhall be judged, as aforeſaid, to be unfit and not Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viceable for the Vſe of the ſaid Hoſpital hereby intended, as alſo to Convert, Alter and Fit ſuch of the preſent Structures as ſhall be Appointed to ſtand, as aforeſaid, in ſuch Manner as ſhall be Appointed, as aforeſaid; And alſo from and after ſuch time as We ſhall have Approved and Allowed of ſuch Model or Models as you ſhall have pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented, as aforeſaid, under Our Sign Manual, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe ſhall have Allowed or Approved of any Model, Scheme or Deſign, for Building, Fitting or Furniſhing the ſaid Hoſpital, to put in Hand, Carry on, and Finiſh, with ſuch Convenient Speed as the nature of the thing, and ſuch Moneys as ſhall be in the Hands of the ſaid Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurer or Receiver, will admit, the Buildings and Structures of the ſaid Hoſpital, and of all the Offices and Conveni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>encies belonging thereto, and to Furniſh the ſame accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingly: In the doing of which, you are to purſue ſuch Models, Orders and Directions as ſhall be Approved or Appointed by Vs, under Our Sign Manual, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid. And Our Pleaſure is, That you ſhall Proceed in the ſaid Works in ſuch Order and Method, and by ſuch Ways and Means, and according to ſuch Rules and Orders as to you ſhall ſeem beſt; And that you ſhall call to your Aid and Aſſiſtance ſuch Skilful Artiſts, Officers and Work<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men as you ſhall think fit, and to Appoint to them ſever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally their reſpective Charge or Buſineſs; And that you Our ſaid Commiſſioners, or any Seven or more of you, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of any one or more of you Our Privy Councellors, and one
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:63191:9"/> or more of you the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury, and any one or more of you the Commiſſioners for Executing the Office of Our High Admiral of <hi>England</hi> for the time being, to be Threé at the leaſt, ſhall, by Warrants in Writing, Direct the Iſſuing, Payment, Allowances and Expenditure of the Moneys or Profits to be Contributed, Given, Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queathed, Deviſed or Appointed, as aforeſaid, to buy or pay for Timber, Brick, Stone or other Materials, and for Furniſhing the ſaid Hoſpital with Beds and other Neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaries and Conveniencies, and to Pay Neceſſary and Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable Sallaries, Wages and Rewards to the ſaid Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſts, Officers and Workmen which ſhall be Employed in the Building, as aforeſaid, and to Reward thoſe who ſhall be neceſſarily Employed in Bringing in, Receiving, Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing or Accounting for the Moneys of the ſaid Contributi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, and to Defray all other Charges and Expences In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cident to the Execution of this Our Commiſſion, or any Part thereof, in ſuch Proportions, Manner and Form, as you ſhall, from time to time, Iudge Reaſonable and Meét. And that you or ſuch of you as are laſt mentioned, ſhall and do Conſider, Adviſe, Agree upon and Set down Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular Orders and Inſtructions, as well for the ſafe Keeping of the Money, from time to time, to be brought into the Treaſury, and of the Materials and Proviſions, from time to time, to be brought into the Stores, as for the Faithful and Frugal Iſſuing out, and Diſpoſing of the ſame for the Publick Vſe intended, and none other; And to Direct and Appoint by whom, and in what man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, the Books and Accounts of both ſhall be, from time to time, Kept, Comptrolled, Audited and Allowed, and out of your own Number, and ſuch other Perſons of known Integrity and Ability, as you ſhall Chooſe, from time to time, and as often as you ſhall Iudge it Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pedient to Appoint, Conſtitute and Make ſuch and ſo ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Sub-committees as you ſhall think meet, for the bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Managing and Carrying on of the ſaid Works, and to Inveſt them with Power to make Contracts, and to do any other Matters or Things, which you ſhall think fit to Entruſt them with, Purſuant to the Power hereby given to your ſelves, and to Revoke and make Void the ſame, and to Revive and make New the ſaid Sub-committees, or any other, when and as often as you ſhall find it needful: And you or ſuch of you as are laſt mentioned, are to Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſe, Treat, Conſider and Determine of all other Matters, Ways and Means, for the Advancement of this Vſeful and Neceſſary Deſign, and to put the ſame in Execution, till
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:63191:10"/> the ſaid Hoſpital ſhall be Compleatly Built, Finiſhed and Furniſhed with all Things neceſſary thereunto. And further, We do, for Vs, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare and Grant to you Our ſaid Commiſſioners, and every of you, That you Our ſaid Commiſſioners, and every of you, ſhall be only Accountable and Anſwerable to Vs, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, for your own reſpective Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipts, Actings or Doings, and not for the Receipts, Actings or Doings of one another, or of the Treaſurer here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by Appointed or to be Appointed. Provided always, and Our Pleaſure is, and We do hereby Direct, Grant and Appoint, That the ſaid <hi>John Evelyn,</hi> hereby Appointed to be the Treaſurer and Receiver General, as aforeſaid, ſhall and may, during his Continuance in that Truſt, for his Pains and Service in the Execution thereof, Have, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive, Retain and Keep out of the Moneys that ſhall from time to time be in his Hands by Virtue or Means of his Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipt, the Yearly Sallary or Allowance of Two hundred Pounds of Lawful <hi>Engliſh</hi> Money, at the Four moſt uſual Feaſts in the Year, by equal Portions, to Commence from the Feaſt of the Annunciation of the Bleſſed Virgin <hi>Mary,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred ninety five, and to be from time to time Allowed upon his Accounts; any thing herein Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained to the contrary notwithſtanding. And theſe Our Letters Patents, or the Entry, Exemplification, or En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rollment thereof, ſhall be to you, and every of you, and all others herein Concerned, a ſufficient Warrant on this be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half: In Witneſs whereof We have Cauſed theſe Our Letters to be made Patents.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Witneſs Our Self at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> 
                  <date>the Twelfth Day of <hi>March,</hi> in the Seventh Year of Our Reign.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>
                  <hi>Per Breve de Privato Sigillo.</hi> CHUTE.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed by <hi>Charles Bill,</hi> and the Executrix of <hi>Thomas Newcomb,</hi> deceas'd; Printers to the Kings moſt Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellent Majeſty. 1695.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:63191:10"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
